(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-24T02:27:11.187220",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
イケナイ太陽
Naughty Sun
ちょっとでいいから 見せてくれないか
Could you show me just a little bit?
お前のセクシーフェロモンでオレメロメロ
Your sexy pheromones drive me crazy.
触れちゃいそうでもイケナイのって狂おしくなるほど抑えられないわ
Even if it feels wrong to touch, I can't hold back this madness!
交わす言葉の記憶 遠く口元の動きに揺れ動く
Memories of exchanged words fade as our lips move.
濡れた髪を撫でた そして ah…
I stroked your wet hair, and then, ah...
そんなんじゃダメじゃない
Isn't that just no good?
だってココロの奥は違うんじゃない?
Because deep down inside, aren't you different?
オレの精神 そんなもんじゃない
My spirit isn't like that!
熱く奥で果てたいよ
I want to reach the fiery depths!
きっとキミじゃなきゃヤダよ
I'm sure it has to be you!
オレはイケナイ太陽
I am the Naughty Sun!
赤い糸なんて絵空事でも下心でさえ信じたいの
Even if the red thread is a fantasy, I want to believe in it.
オレは正しい キミも正しい
I'm right, and you're right.
とにかくもう左右されないで
Anyway, don't be swayed either way!
騙し騙され胸疼く 下手な芝居がより盛り上げる夜
Deceiving and being deceived, hearts ache—clumsy acting heats up the night.
息が耳に触れた二人 ah…
Two people whose breath touches each other's ears, ah...
そんなんじゃダメじゃない
Isn't that just no good?
だってココロの奥は違うんじゃない?
Because deep down inside, aren't you different?
あたしの精神 そんなもんじゃない
My spirit isn't like that!
熱く奥で果てたいよ
I want to reach the fiery depths!
きっとキミじゃなきゃヤダよ
I'm sure it has to be you!
あたしイケナイ太陽
I am the Naughty Sun!
交わす言葉の記憶遠く口元の動きに揺れ動く
Memories of exchanged words fade as our lips move.
濡れた髪を撫でた そして ah…
I stroked your wet hair, and then, ah...
ABC…
ABC...
イケナイ太陽 NA NA
Forbidden Sun, na na
チョットでいいから見せてくれないか
Won't you show me just a little bit?
お前のセクシー・フェロモンでオレメロメロ
With your sexy pheromone, making me go crazy
AHふれそうでもイケナイの!
Ah, we might touch, but it's forbidden!
徐々に高鳴る鼓動とまらないわ
My heartbeat gradually pounding, won't stop
交わる言葉の記憶遠く口元に揺れ動く
Memories of exchanged words sway far at your lips
濡れた髪を撫でそとしてAH?
Stroking your wet hair, ah?
ABC続かないそんなんじゃダメじゃない
ABC doesn't last, isn't that no good?
だってココロの奥は違うんじゃない?
Because deep in our hearts, isn't it different?
オレの青春そんなもんじゃない熱く奥で果てたいよ
My youth isn't like that, I want to finish hot and deep
きっとキミじゃなきゃヤダよオレはイケナイ太陽
It has to be you, I'm a forbidden sun
絡み合う糸は君と俺を結ぶ赤い糸NA
The intertwining thread is the red thread connecting you and me
「赤い糸」なんて絵空事でも下心でさえ信じたいの
Even if a red thread is a fantasy, I want to believe in it
俺は正しいキミも正しいとにかくもう左右されないゾ
I'm right, you're right, anyway I won't be swayed either way
はい!ということで、あい皆さんこんばんは!
Hi! So... hi everyone, good evening!
このライブ3周年の、ねっきょ…じゃなくて、白銀ノエルです!
This is Shirogane Noel, celebrating my 3rd anniversary live!
イエイ!いきなり生パートでお送りしております!いや、コメント見てるよ。
Yay! Delivering this live on the spot! Yeah, I'm watching the chat.
「奥で果てるとは」みたいなこと書いてあったけど、
Someone wrote things like "what does 'finish deep inside' mean?"
それはあの、調べてくださいね、ウェブで!
You should look that up on the web!
ていうか、そういう話をしたいんじゃなくて、えっと今回白銀ノエル3周年を迎えました!
I mean, I don't want to talk about that, um, 3rd anniversary!
ハッシュタグ白銀ノエル3周年記念でね、いっぱいつぶやいて、盛り上げてくれると嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you tweet with hashtag #ShiroganeNoel3rdAnniversary.
そして水着です!今日はね、水着とか色々着て夏の思い出を作りたいと思います。尺が1分しかないんでね、急いでいきたいと思います!
And it's swimwear! Today I'm wearing swimwear to make summer memories.
あの一等星のさんざめく光であなたとダンスを踊ろうか
Shall I dance with you in the sparkling light of that first-magnitude star?
我が太陽系の鼓動に合わせて絡まったステップで煌めいて、星っ!
Matching the pulse of our solar system, sparkling with intertwined steps, star!
オー・オ・オー!
Oh-oh-oh!
ランバダンスふたり宇宙でランデブーな妄、患って夜眠れない
Ramba, rumba, the two of us rendezvous in space, sleepless night after night
星座になって混ざるどんな一等星もあなたに変わる光度はないわ
Becoming constellations and mingling—no first-magnitude star compares to you
校舎の裏あの日のあなた見つけた奇跡さえ今は離れない
Behind the school building that day, I found you; that miracle hasn't faded
隣に繁く見える冥王星も生憎今は興味がないわ
Pluto visible beside us holds no interest for me right now
星が舞いちゃって胸が鳴っちゃって気づけば彼方――
Stars are dancing, my chest is pounding, before I knew it, far away...
あの一等星のさんざめく光であなたとダンスを踊ろうか
Shall I dance with you in the glittering light of that first-magnitude star?
我が太陽系の法則に誘われ交わした感度で煌めいて、星っ!
Sucked in by the laws of our solar system, sparkling with crossed sensations, star!
オー・オ・オー!
Oh-oh-oh!
星間線を繋いであなたに届け
Connecting the interstellar lines, reach you
宇宙の果てからあなた侵光系!
From the edge of the universe, you are an invasion system!
大体のダンスは星が光り導きとなのさ未体験なステップでハッハッハッ!
Most dances are guided by twinkling stars, with untried steps, ha ha!
大胆なスタンスで周回軌道上なぞるのさ太陽系のデスコでハッハッハッ!
Tracing along the orbital path with a bold stance, at the solar system's disco!
宙漂っていつかふたり忘れる言葉さえいまは求めたい
Drifting in space, words we might forget are what I want to seek right now
超新星をネガウ暮夜の世界も不思議といまはどうでもいいわ
Even a world darkened by wishing for a supernova doesn't matter now
何もなくなってなんだかなくなって星はめぐって――
Even if there's nothing at all, the stars keep revolving...
あの一等星の届かない光は遥かなかなたで煌めいた
The unreachable light of that first-magnitude star sparkled in the beyond
我が太陽系の法則も外れて「それでもいいさ」手を伸ばして!
Even breaking solar laws, "Even so, that's fine," reaching out!
さあ、幾星霜と宿した想いであなたのすべて求めようか
With feelings harbored across star-frosts, shall I seek your everything?
ねえ、何光年の巨大な旅路で比翼の連理を探そうか
On a vast journey of light-years, shall we search for the twin-wing connection?
あの一等星のさんざめく光であなたとダンスを踊ろうか
Shall I dance with you in the glittering light of that first-magnitude star?
ほら水金だって地火木土天海もふたりの銀河で煌めいた、星っ!
Look, Mercury, Venus, Earth, Mars, Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus, Neptune—sparkled!
オー・オ・オー! 星間線を繋いで
Oh-oh-oh! Connecting the interstellar lines
あなたに届け
Reach you,
宇宙の果てから オー・オー・オー!
From the edge of the universe, oh!
あなた 一等星!
Reach you, first-magnitude star!
ラララ...
La la la...
ふう!
Phew!
はぁ、はぁ、はぁ!
Phew, phew, phew!
いや、やばいやばい、やばいやばい!
No, way too fast, way too fast!
あぁあぁあぁ!
Ah, ah, ah, ah!
お!
Oh!
3周年おめでとうございます!
Congratulations on your 3rd anniversary!
やったー!
Yay!
ちょっと待って、ちょっと目をつぶって!目をつぶって!
Wait, wait, close your eyes! Close your eyes!
興奮しすぎてしまった。
I got too excited.
いや、ちょっと、団長ね、えっと。
Wait, first, the leader,ねえ。
こよちゃんがまさか、団長のライブに来てくれるなんて!
To think Koyori would come to the leader's live!
嬉しい!
I'm so happy!
こよーりのホロックスもまさか、こよちゃんが呼んでくれたんで!ありがとうございます!
Koyori's holoX even called me! Thank you so much!
しかもですね、実を言うと、こよーり、
And actually, Koyori...
この3Dで、こうゲストにさせていただくの、今日が初めてなんです!
Today is the first time in 3D that I'm appearing as a guest!
初めて3Dで!やったー!
First time in 3D! Yay!
初めて3Dで!やりましたー!
いや、ちょっと嬉しいけど、でも、その席には取りません。
I'm so happy, but... I won't take responsibility for this seat!
え?ちょっと待って、こっちが先に責任...
Eh? Wait, which one is taking responsibility first?
いや、こよちゃんだったら、そういうこと言うだろうなと思って。えっ!
Because if it's Koyori, she'd say something like that, so I thought...
えっ、じゃあ先に取ってくれないんですか?
Eh? You won't take it first?
こよちゃん、えっ、なんかしてほしいこと、あったりする?
Koyori, uh, is there something you want me to do? Will you do it?
えっ、じゃあ、ちょっと、あの、後ろから抱きしめてもいいですか?
Then, um, can you hug me from behind?
ちょっと、いいんですか?
Is that okay?
初めての、そういうさ、先輩とのMCというか。
My first time doing this kind of senpai-kohai MC thing...
あ、だからこそ、こうなんか、好きなこと言っちゃってもいいかなとか思って。じゃあ、ちょっといいですよ。
So I thought it'd be okay to ask for your favorite things!
いい、いいんですか?
Is that okay?
はい、じゃあ、おいでさん。
All right, then, come here.
これ、なんか、たい、あ、タイト?
Tight? Tight?
風を感じるー!
Feel the wind!
ちょっ、えっ、嬉しい。あっ、見て、脇、お互い見えるで。
Ah, I'm so happy. Oh, look, our armpits are visible to each other!
本当だ!
Really!
これが、脇ライブ。
This is... armpit live.
そうだね。こよちゃん、これからいっぱい脇ライブしていこうな!はい!していこうね。
That's right. Koyori, let's do lots of armpit live shows from now on!
よし、それでは、この後も楽しんでくださいね!
Well then, please enjoy the rest of the show!
はい!そう、この後ね、団長もちょっとお着替えして変わるからさ、一緒に帰るかい?
Yes! And after that, the leader will change clothes, so let's go back together!
あ、一緒にっていいんですか?
Is that okay?
まあ、いいよ、いいよ。
Good, good, good.
落ち着いて、落ち着いて。もちろん、団長についてけばね、大丈夫だからここか。
Calm down, calm down. Of course, if we follow the leader, it'll be fine.
あ、段差とかあるからね、気をつけて。行こ、じゃあ、二人とも一緒。行きましょう。
There might be steps, so be careful. Okay, let's go together.
さあ、次はいくぜ!あ、やばい、落ちた!
Next is... Whoa, whoa, I'm falling!
ドキッ!こういうのが恋なの?
Doki! Is this what you call love?
はい!はい!はい!はい!
Yeah!
ねぇ、歌うわ、そうよあなたに。
Singing is all for you!
甘えたいけねぇと恥ずかしがってもね。 (はぁ、もね!)
I want to cuddle, but I'm a bit embarrassed too. (Yeah, me too!)
願いごとのちゅうの。 ほら、むニャむニャむニャ! (はい!はい!はい!はい!)
A wish-fulfilling... (Hey!) Munya-munya-munya! (Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!)
ずっとこのまま時が止まらぬかもね。 (はぁ、もね!)
Staying just like this, time might stop, you know? (Yeah, me too!)
こういうのが恋なの、ドキドキドキ!
This kind of thing... this kind of thing... makes my heart go doki-doki-doki!
しかもね、 (はぁ、もね!) 好き好き好き!
And even... (Yeah, me too!) Suki-suki-suki!
昨日よりも、 (はぁ、もね!) むニャむニャむニャ!
More than yesterday... (Yeah, me too!) Munya-munya-munya!
はい!はい!はい! はい!はい!はい!はい!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
かもね、 (はぁ、もね!) 好き好き好き!
Come on! (Yeah, me too!) Suki-suki-suki!
しかもね、 (はぁ、もね!) 好き好き好き!
And even... (Yeah, me too!) Suki-suki-suki!
おトメの気持ちが伝わるといいな、いいな。 (はい!)
I hope an adult's feelings reach you! (Good, good!)
どっとからできそうなくらい、 もんラブ、ラブ、ラブ!
I have a feeling it might... (Love, love, love!)
はい!はい!はい!はい!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
好き好き好き! (はい!はい!はい!はい!)
Suki-suki-suki! (Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!)
なーにしよっか 練習中
What should I do? In practice,
しれっとこっそり 準備進行
Quietly making preparations,
心境緊張で 焦る
Anxious and nervous inside,
言うんけどうそよ アリでしょ？
I say that, but a little fib is fine, right?
元気配るから 待ちちょって
I'll spread my energy, so wait for me,
そうやって 成長する子です
That's how a child grows.
いいかな？
Is that okay?
ゆるポンで OK？
Laid-back style is OK?
いちにーさん
One, two, three,
テンパっちゃって OK？
Panicking a bit is OK?
始めちゃおう
Let's get started!
ほめてほしいな
I want you to praise me,
ほめてくれたら 2割増しで頑張る
If you praise me, I'll work 20% harder!
見ててほしいな
I want you to watch me,
ほめちぎられて伸びるタイプです
I grow when praised endlessly.
もうーお
Oh well...
なーんにも出てない
Nothing's coming out at all,
頭ん中真っ白ださっぱりだ
My mind is completely blank and empty.
うーんうーん　あれ？
Hmm... huh?
まいっか
Oh well!
凹凸な情緒提供中
Delivering bumpy emotions right now,
ぽかんとして何しちゃおんの
Looking dazed, what am I even doing?
こんなんが通常のわたし
This is my usual self,
いいでしょ？
Pretty good, right?
それでは OK？
So is that OK?
いちにーさん
One, two, three,
落ち着き OK？
Staying calm is OK?
始めちゃおう
Let's get started!
どうしたらいいの
What should I do?
どうすればみんな ハッピーで笑顔バッチリ
How to make everyone happy with big smiles?
こちらへどうぞ
Right this way, please,
押さず慌てず並んで合図です
Queue up calmly, no pushing, on my cue.
もうーお
Oh well...
聞こえてる
Can you hear it?
みんみんみんーら
Meow, meow, meow...
楽しんでき
Are you having fun?
ぱむぱむぱーむ
Pam, pam, pam...
こっちだよ
Over here!
少し眠いな
I'm a little sleepy,
また明日食べて寝て今は成長期
Eat, sleep, and grow tomorrow too.
夢を見たいな
I want to dream,
どうぞくれぐれもあの、今後も
Please, from now on too,
ほめてほしいな
I want you to praise me,
ほめてくれたら2割増しで頑張る
If you praise me, I'll work 20% harder!
見ててほしいな
I want you to watch me,
ほめちぎられて伸びるタイプです
I grow when praised endlessly.
またね
See you!
聞こえてる
Can you hear it?
みんみんみんーら
Meow, meow, meow...
楽しんでき
Are you having fun?
ぱむぱむぱーむ
Pam, pam, pam...
こっちだよ
Over here!
少し眠いな
I'm a little sleepy,
また明日食べて寝て今は成長期
Eat, sleep, and grow tomorrow too.
夢を見たいな
I want to dream,
どうぞくれぐれもあの、今後も
Please, from now on too,
ほめてほしいな
I want you to praise me,
ほめてくれたら2割増しで頑張る
If you praise me, I'll work 20% harder!
見ててほしいな
I want you to watch me,
ほめちぎられて伸びるタイプです
I grow when praised endlessly.
ほめてほしいな
I want you to praise me,
ほめてくれたら2割増しで頑張る
If you praise me, I'll work 20% harder!
見ててほしいな
I want you to watch me,
ほめちぎられて伸びるタイプです
I grow when praised endlessly.
またね
See you!
あい！ということで、えっと、水着だよー！イエーイ！
Alright! So, um, it's swimwear! Yay!
びっくりした、びっくりした、びっくりした！
I was so surprised, so surprised, so surprised!
ということで、えっと、水着になってからは、ドキッこういうのが恋なのとほめのびを続けて歌わせていただきました！歌ってダンスしました！
So after changing into swimwear, we sang and danced consecutively to 'Doki! Kouiu no ga Koi nano?' and 'Homenobi'!
いや、ちょっとね、団長気づいた人いるかなって思ってちょっとチラチラ見てたんですけど、そう太陽系デス子、ドキッこういうのが恋なのとほめのび、この3曲
I wondered if anyone noticed, so I kept glancing around. Yes, 'Taiyoukei Death Co', 'Doki!', and 'Homenobi', these 3 songs,
ファーストFesからねサードFesまでの団長のソロで歌った曲になります！
These are the solo songs I performed from the 1st Fes to the 3rd Fes!
え、でもなんかちょっと2曲続けてはね、やっぱりちょっとね、あー団長ちょっともっともっと体力つけたいなと、思いまして！
Singing two songs in a row... I realized Dancho wants to build up even more stamina!
で、こっからソロではなく、ゲストさんを呼んで歌って踊ってやりますので、まだまだ盛り上がっていってください！では行ってきまーす！まだまだみてねー！
From here on, instead of solo, we'll invite guests to sing and dance, so keep the hype going! Off I go!
絶対絶命サマーナイト　突撃ゲットおるナイト
Zettai Zetsumei Summer Night, Totsugeki Get All Night!
絶体絶命！
Desperate situation!
summer night
完遂決定！
Decided to pull an all-nighter!
all night
ヤバイ！ヤバイ！まじでヤバイ！
This is bad! Bad! Seriously bad!
（ヤバイ！）
(Bad!)
la la la la……
La la la la...
what a night!
灼熱太陽の下で
Under the scorching sun,
こんがり小麦色
tanned to a crisp
ライブ ビキニ きもだめし
Live shows, bikinis, tests of bravery,
さっこうの夏休み！
a perfect summer vacation!
ふと気付けば31日
Before I knew it, it was the 31st,
真っ青ナスビ色
I was pale as an eggplant
ずっとカバン眠ってた
Sleeping in my backpack the whole time
手付かず山積みプリント
was a huge pile of untouched worksheets.
クエストン！
Question!
x＋y＝？ “CIA！”
X + Y = ? “CIA!”
オーストラリアの首都は？ “ありません！”
What is the capital of Australia? “There isn’t one!”
法隆寺を建てたのは？ “卑弥呼様！”
Who built the Houryuuji shrine? “Lady Himiko!”
意味不明！
Nonsense!
where do you live now? “yes, i do！”
Where do you live now? “Yes, I do!”
酸素を作るには？ “ワニとシャンプー！”
What is oxygen made of? “Alligators and shampoo!”
ヤバイ！ヤバイ！yabai！しゃぶぁい！yabai！
This is bad! Bad! Bad! Bad! Bad!
まじヤバすぎる！
Seriously beyond bad!
終わらない 終わらない
It’s unending, unending,
ぜーん ぜん ぜーんぜん 終わらない
Absolutely, absolutely unending
8月 最終日の 宿題！
Homework on the last day of August
てきとにやってもしょうがない でも
Gotta do it sloppily,
てきとにやるしかないしゃうかない
sloppily is the only way I can do it
とりあえずひたすらかきまくれーー！！
For the time being, all I can do is write what comes out!
わからない わからない
I don’t get it, don’t get it,
ぜーん ぜん ぜーんぜん わからない
Absolutely, absolutely don’t get it!
もう少し手加減してよ 宿題！
Take it easy on me a little bit, homework!
誰かのせいにはしたくない でも
I don’t want it to be anyone’s fault, but
自分のせいにはしたくない
I don’t want it to be my fault!
残り80枚！
80 pages remaining of
終わらない 宿題
Unending homework
絶体絶命！
Desperate situation!
summer night
完遂決定！
Decided to pull an all-nighter!
all night
ヤバイ！ヤバイ！まじでヤバイ！
This is bad! Bad! Seriously bad!
（ヤバイ！）
(Bad!)
la la la la……
La la la la...
what a night!
終業式から今日が来るまで
From the closing ceremonies until today,
毎日かけぬけた
everyday has flown by
キャンプ イベント スイカ割り
Camping, events, watermelon-splitting,
大切な思い出
all precious memories
忘れてたわけじゃないけれど
It’s not that I forgot, but
大きな忘れ物
there was something big that was forgotten
きっとなんとかなるでしょ？
Surely it’ll work out somehow?
シャープペン握って対決！！
I’ll grip my pencil and have a showdown!!
かかれー！
Start it!
読書感想文 “使いまわし！”
Book report “Reuse one!”
お天気 “毎日くもり！”
The weather “Everyday was cloudy!”
ヤバイ！ヤバイ！yabai！しゃぶぁい！yabai！
This is bad! Bad! Bad! Bad! Bad!
まじヤバすぎる！
Seriously beyond bad!
終わらない 終わらない
It’s unending, unending,
ぜーん ぜん ぜーんぜん 終わらない
Absolutely, absolutely unending
8月 最終日の 宿題！
Homework on the last day of August
こうかいしてたってしょうがない でも
Gotta have regrets about it,
こうかいするしかないしょうがない
There’s no choice but to have regrets about it!
神様 一学期 戻してよっっっ！！
God, send me back to the first semester!
わからない わからない
I don’t get it, don’t get it,
ぜーん ぜん ぜーんぜん わからない
Absolutely, absolutely don’t get it!
もう少し手加減してよ 宿題！
Take it easy on me a little bit, homework!
言い訳なんかはしたくない でも
I don’t want to make excuses, but
言い訳するしかないしかたがない
I have no choice but to make excuses!
残り70枚！
70 pages remaining of
終わらない 宿題
Unending homework
時間だけでも過ぎてゆくけれど
Time keeps passing by, but
出口はまだまだ先の先
The exit is still ahead of ahead
SOSメールを出しても
Even though I sent an SOS email
送信ゼロ件・・・・
I got zero replies…
自業自得 因果応報
You reap what you sow, divine retribution,
四面楚歌
Surrounded by the enemy
二学期なんか来なくてもいい
If only the 2nd semester wouldn’t come…
はぁ・・・・おわんない
Ugh, it never ends…
終わらない 終わらない
It’s unending, unending,
ぜーん ぜん ぜーんぜん 終わらない
Absolutely, absolutely unending
8月 最終日の 宿題！
Homework on the last day of August
てきとにやってもしょうがない でも
Gotta do it sloppily,
てきとにやるしかないしょうがない
Sloppily is the only way I can do it
とりあえずひたすらかきまくれーー！！
For the time being, all I can do is write what comes out!
わからない わからない
I don’t get it, don’t get it,
ぜーん ぜん ぜーんぜん わからない
Absolutely, absolutely don’t get it!
もう少し手加減してよ 宿題！
Take it easy on me a little bit, homework!
誰かのせいにはしたくない でも
I don’t want it to be anyone’s fault, but
自分のせいにはしたくない
I don’t want it to be my fault!
残り60枚！
60 pages remaining of
終わらない 宿題
Unending homework
時間だけでも過ぎてゆくけれど
Time keeps passing by, but
出口はまだまだ先の先
The exit is still ahead of ahead
SOSメールを出しても
Even though I sent an SOS email
送信ゼロ件・・・・
I got zero replies…
自業自得 因果応報
You reap what you sow, divine retribution,
四面楚歌
Surrounded by the enemy
二学期なんか来なくてもいい
If only the 2nd semester wouldn’t come…
あぁ・・・・おわんない
Ugh, it never ends…
終わらない 終わらない
It’s unending, unending,
ぜーん ぜん ぜーんぜん 終わらない
Absolutely, absolutely unending
8月 最終日の 宿題！
Homework on the last day of August
てきとにやってもしょうがない でも
Gotta do it sloppily,
てきとにやるしかないしょうがない
Sloppily is the only way I can do it
とりあえずひたすらかきまくれーー！！
For the time being, all I can do is write what comes out!
わからない わからない
I don’t get it, don’t get it,
ぜーん ぜん ぜーんぜん わからない
Absolutely, absolutely don’t get it!
もう少し手加減してよ 宿題！
Take it easy on me a little bit, homework!
誰かのせいにはしたくない でも
I don’t want it to be anyone’s fault, but
自分のせいにはしたくない
I don’t want it to be my fault!
残り60枚！
60 pages remaining of
終わらない 宿題
Unending homework
おめでとーー！
Happy anniversary!
三周年おめでとーー！
Happy 3rd anniversary!
いやちょっとね、いや、だってさ！
Wait a minute, I mean, come on!
だってさ、三期生みんなさ、夏デビューじゃないですか！
I mean, all of us in the 3rd gen had our summer debuts, right?!
夏デビューに、夏の曲をね、しかも水着で！
Our summer debuts, with summer songs, and in swimsuits!
歌っておどるなら、やばい、やばい！
If we're singing and dancing, this is so bad!
そう！だってさ、うちらね、水着なかったからさ、そう！すごーい嬉しいんだよね！
That's right! Because we didn't have swimsuits back then, so we're super happy!
そうのね、三期生の頃でしたからね、あの、ホロライブサマーが...
Yeah, back in the 3rd gen days, Hololive Summer was...
あの、なんかフレアがさ、ペコラっちをちょっと煽ってさ、
Flare kind of provoked Pekora a little bit,
だからさ、もうせっかくだからさ、この海を背景にさ、写真とか撮っちゃいませんか？撮りたーい！
So since we're here, why don't we take some photos against this ocean backdrop? Let's take some!
おおー！
Oooh!
どんな？
What kind?
でも、やっぱさ、これ、扇子あれだからさ、
But still, since we have these folding fans here,
やっぱこ、こんな感じで扇子っぽくさ、やろうぜ。
let's do it like fan dancing. Like fan dancing,
体、体こうやってさ、こうやってさ、
and move our bodies like this, like this,
みんなで扇子を作る。
everyone make a fan shape.
え、どういうことね？
Eh, what do you mean?
じゃあ船長、えっと、こうじゃん？
Then Captain, um, like this?
あいね？
Right?
そうそうそうそう、イエーイ！
That's right, yeah!
で、これが撮りたかったの？
And, was this what you wanted to capture?
どんな絵柄？
What kind of picture?
撮りたくないこと... 違くないか？
Things we don't want... Isn't that wrong?
なんかさ、こう、みんなでさ、こうやってさ、仮面舞踏、マスカレードよ。
Like some sort of... everyone doing this, masquerade.
あいじゃん！
Right!
え、それなんか、マリアがするとあれだな、
Eh, but if Maria does it, that's...
え、何、どういうのの、どういうのね？
Eh, what, wh- what do you mean?
顔を隠すの、こうやってね、こうね。
Hiding our faces, like this, like this.
隙間からね、隙間からね。
Through the gap, through the gap.
え、本当 にこれでいいのか？
Eh, really, is this good?
なんかさ、おんちょ、なんと、なんと、なんか...
Ah, somehow, somehow...
なんで、みんなで写真撮るの？
Why are we taking pictures together?
元気出して！マリアはノエル王だから、マリアはノエル王だよ。
Cheer up! Maria is Noel-ou, Maria is Noel-ou.
そうだよ、そうだよ。
That's right, that's right.
あの、今ね、絶賛さ、夏は三期生のさ、4週連続企画で、
Um, right now, currently, summer is the 3rd gen's 4-week consecutive project,
明日はペコラっちの分かりてえわが！
and tomorrow is Pekora-chi's "I understand"!
誰がペコラっちのこと分かるかね？
Who would understand Pekora-chi?
絶対勝つ！絶対勝つ！絶対勝つ！絶対勝つ！
Definitely win! Definitely win! Definitely win! Definitely win!
楽しみペコでしょ、でよね。
You're looking forward to it, right?
そう、だからね、ちょっと、まあ、みんなちょっとここでね、あの、今日はバイバイしちゃうけど、明日も会えるからね。
So, that's why, you know, everyone will say goodbye here today, but we can meet tomorrow too.
そうだ、そうだ。楽しみだね。
That's right, I'm looking forward to it.
じゃあ二人で行くか？うん、二人で行こう、行こう。
Then shall the two of us go? Yeah, let's go.
じゃあ、じゃあね、バイバーイ！
Well then, bye-bye!
じゃあ明日もよろしくね。あ、ライブまだ続くよー。
See you tomorrow too. Ah, the live stream is still continuing~
ドコドコあそこ見つからないぜ
Can't find it anywhere over there,
パパイヤ マンゴー ココナッツ
Papaya, mango, coconut,
書き込み！イチゴ味 ゼロを直したら 真っ赤っか！
Posting! Strawberry flavor, fixing the zero makes it bright red!
もっと出して！澄み切った一滴
Give me more! A crystal clear drop,
ちょ、ちょ、ちょ、ちょ、ちょっ！
Cho-cho-cho-cho-cho!
ココナッツ！ カチカチに燃えてるお日さま
Coconut! The sun burning hard,
夏はココナッツベイベ
Summer is coconut baby!
街はみた 季節は様々
The town has seen various seasons,
夏はココナッツベイベ
Summer is coconut baby!
甘いキッスで かっちゃったビキニ
In a bikini won with a sweet kiss,
ちょっぴり照れるけど負けらんない
Feeling a bit shy, but I can't lose,
引き止めココナッツでいざ！
Now stopping with coconut!
夏はココナッツベイベ
Summer is coconut baby!
白い線とココナッツでいざ！
Now with white lines and coconut!
夏はココナッツベイベ
Summer is coconut baby!
打球、特急、君の視線
Batting, express train, your gaze,
心臓、大爆発！
Heart, huge explosion!
描き出してココナッツベイベ
Drawing out coconut baby,
抱き合って行こうでココナッツベイベ
let's hug and go coconut baby,
掻っ切ってけココナッツベイベ 夏・夏・サマータイム！
Slash through coconut baby, summer, summer, summertime!
鍵盤通り メロン味 メロンを出したらゾンビの愛
Keyboard-style melon flavor, adding melon is zombie's love,
勝負行くぜ飛んで踊ってせぇの！
Let's go for the match, fly and dance, ready, go!
ちょいな ちょいな ちょいな ちょいな
Choina choina choina choina,
虫々うんざり 得て得ていや！
Sick of bugs, getting it, no way!
夏はココナッツベイベ
Summer is coconut baby!
ココナッツ中休みたいの
Coconut, I want to take a break mid-way,
夏はココナッツベイベ
Summer is coconut baby!
長い両手短い背 待たせた
Long arms, short back, kept you waiting,
やっちゃんタモンが神！
Yacchan Tamon is god!
描き出してココナッツベイベ
Drawing out coconut baby,
抱き合って行こうでココナッツベイベ
let's hug and go coconut baby,
掻っ切ってけココナッツベイベ 夏・夏・サマータイム！
Slash through coconut baby, summer, summer, summertime!
フライアー！スットコポッキー！
Flyer! Suttoko Pocky!
ディディディボウファイワー！
Didi di bow fire!
あっちこっちのサマー ぶっつり針葉樹
Summer here and there, sharply cut conifer,
美味しきアマジャッパ！
Delicious ama-jappa!
ココナツ ベイベー ざっぴゅんで
Coco-nut baby, with a splash!
かきくけココナツ ベイベー
Kakiku-ke coco-nut baby!
サンサンサマータイム イェー!
Sun-sun summer time, yeah!
ココ☆ナッツ オーナツ
Coco☆Nuts, O-nuts!
ココココココココ オーナツ
Coco-coco-coco-coco O-nuts!
パパイヤマンゴー ココナッツ!
Papaya mango coconut!
いやー！きゃー！
No way! Ahh!
ちょっと待って！みんなこっちこっち！
Wait a minute! Everyone over here!
カメラさ、こっちこっちだよカメラさ！
The camera's over here, over here!
わしゃーわしゃー！わしゃわしゃー！イェーイ！夏だー！
Splash splash! Yeah! It's summer!
白銀ノエル先輩3周年おめでとうございます！
Congratulations on Shirogane Noel-senpai's 3rd anniversary!
おめでとうございまーす！
Congratulations!
かわいい！
So cute!
罪の可愛さよ。いや、我々水着ですよ？そうだよ、水着！
Such sinful cuteness. We're in swimsuits, right?
水着ー！ちょっとみんなの水着とかやばっ！
Swimsuits! Everyone's swimsuits are amazing!
やばめー！
So crazy!
いや、なんかね、団長、あれですよ、やっぱね、桃クロの曲、このメンバーで歌ったのも理由分かるよね？
There's a reason why we chose Momoiro Clover's song for this lineup, right?
もちろん！もちろん！あれ？みんな分かるよね？わかるよね！
Of course! Huh? Everyone gets it, right?
じゃあ、せーのでいきましょう。私たち、モノノフの、モノノフ曲で！
Alright, let's go on three. With a Mononofu song!
ココナツ ベイベー ざっぴゅんで！
Coco-nut baby, with a splash!
いやでも、しかもある、今回さ、歌って踊って見に行いて気づいたんだけど、この曲にいいわ。
Having sung and danced to it, I realized how great this song is.
そもそもそれぞれ系統がいて、めちゃくちゃバランスがいいなって思いました。
Everyone has their own style, so the balance is really great.
なんか属性がもう分かれてるもんね。そうそうそう！
It's like our attributes are already distinct. Exactly!
4人でさ、ちょっと写真撮りません？結構水着ですからね。
Shall we take a picture together? Since we're in swimsuits.
じゃあ、縦になって、こう振り返って……振り返り美人ね。
Line up vertically and turn back... like a beauty looking back.
やばっ！やばっ！ちょ、ぽるか、尻がやばくてさ。
Whoa! Polka, your tail looks crazy!
ちょっと待って、後ろ向いて、ちゃんと！後ろ向いて、ちゃんと！可愛い！
Turn around properly! Turn around! So cute!
これが、これが、これが、これか！るい、るいね、尻ないの？これ、尻？
So this is it! Lui, do you not have a tail? Is this a tail?
魚だから、ないのよ！
Because I'm a fish, I don't have one!
えー！あ、可愛い！あ、可愛いねー！
Ehh! Ah, so cute!
イェーイ！イェーイ！暖かい！ハッシュタグでつぶやいてねー！
Yay! Yay! Warm! Tweet with the hashtag, okay?
イェーイ！わあ！いや、みんな暑い。団長、団長めっちゃ汗出てる！
Yay! Wow, everyone's hot. Leader, you're sweating so much!
いや、なんかさ、あれだもん、でも時間がね、限られててさ。
Well, you know, our time is limited after all.
え？もうそろそろ？
Eh? Already?
ここにいたい！ここにいたい！足ふやけちゃうからね！
I want to stay here! Our feet are going to get pruney!
え、じゃあさ、でもさ、やっぱ、団長もね、このあとね、あれなんですよ。
Well, you know, Leader has something coming up after this too.
ちょっと、海からね、ちょっと、変わりましてなんで、お着替えするんで。
Changing out of the ocean gear, so I'm going to change clothes.
みんなと一緒に、お着替えしたいから。
Because I want to change clothes together with everyone.
じゃあ、お着替えしようか。しゃあ、シャワー浴びる？
Shall we change then? Want to take a shower?
シャワー浴びよ！じゃあ、一緒にシャワー浴びよ！
Let's take a shower! Let's take a shower together!
じゃあ、いきますよ！一緒にシャワー、いきます！
Alright, here we go! Shower together!
せーの！の！
Ready, set—!
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if I've forgotten already,
夏の木陰に座ったまま、氷菓子を口に放り込んで風を待っていた
sitting in the summer shade, tossing ice candy into my mouth and waiting for the breeze.
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if I've forgotten already,
世の中の全部嘘ばっかり、本当の価値を二人で探しに行こうと笑ったこと
that we laughed about searching the world for true value amidst all its lies.
忘れないように
So I won't forget,
色褪せないように
so it won't fade,
形に残るものが全てじゃないように
so that things left in form aren't everything.
言葉をもっと教えて
Teach me more words,
夏が来るって教えて
teach me that summer is coming.
僕は描いている、目に映ったのは夏の亡霊だ
I am sketching; what was reflected in my eyes was a summer ghost.
風にスカートが揺れて
My skirt sways in the breeze,
思い出なんて忘れて
forgetting even memories,
浅い呼吸をする、汗を拭いて夏めく
taking shallow breaths, wiping sweat, feeling the summer.
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if I've forgotten already...
Have I forgotten it already?
夏の木陰に座った頃を
When I sat in the shade of the summer trees
遠くの丘から顔出した雲があったじゃないか
Wasn't there a cloud peeking out from the distant hill?
君はそれを掴もうとして
You tried to grab hold of it,
馬鹿みたいに空を切った手で
With your hand slicing the air foolishly,
僕は紙に雲一つを描いて笑って握って見せて
I drew a single cloud on paper, smiling as I held it out
忘れないように
So I won't forget it,
色褪せないように
So it won't fade away,
歴史に残るものが全てじゃないから
Because everything isn't just what remains in history
今だけ顔も無くして
Losing even my face right now,
言葉も全部忘れて
Forgetting all words completely,
君は笑ってる、夏を待っている僕ら亡霊だ
You're smiling, we're ghosts waiting for summer
心をもっと教えて
Tell me more about your heart,
夏の匂いを教えて
Tell me the smell of summer,
浅い呼吸をする
Taking a shallow breath
忘れないように
So I won't forget it,
色褪せないように
So it won't fade away,
心に響くものが全てじゃないから
Because not everything is just what echoes in the heart
言葉をもっと教えて
Tell me more words,
さよならだって教えて
Tell me it's a goodbye, too,
今も見いるんだよ、夏に咲いている花に亡霊を
I still see them, ghosts blooming in the summer flowers
言葉じゃなくて時間を
Time instead of words,
時間じゃなくて心を
Heart instead of time,
浅い呼吸をする、汗を拭って夏めく、夏の匂いがする
Taking a shallow breath, wiping sweat, feeling the summer scent
夏の匂いがする
I can smell the summer
もう忘れてしまったかな
Have I forgotten it already?
夏の木陰に座ったまま
Sitting in the shade of the summer trees,
アイスを口に放り込んで、風を待っていた
Throwing ice cream into my mouth and waiting for the wind
あなたは今どこで何をしていますか
Where are you now, what are you doing?
この空の続く場所にいますか
Are you in the place where this sky goes on?
今までは私の中心に埋めていたモノ
The things that had filled the center of my heart until now,
失って初めて気付いた
I realized only after losing them
こんなにも私を支えてくれていたこと
How much you had supported me,
こんなにも笑顔をくれていたこと
How much you had given me your smile
失ってしまった代償はとてつもなく大きすぎて
The price of losing you is far too immensely vast
取り戻そうと必死に手を伸ばしてもがいても
Even if I desperately reach out and struggle to take it back
まるで風のようにすり抜けて届きそうで届かない
Like the wind, it slips through, seeming close yet out of reach
孤独と絶望に胸を締め付けられ
My chest is tightened by loneliness and despair
心が壊れそうになるけれど
My heart feels like it will break, but...
思い出に残るあなたの笑顔が私をいつも励ましてくれる
Your smiling face in my memories always encourages me
もう一度あの頃に戻ろう
Let's return to those days once more
今度はきっと大丈夫
This time I'm sure it will be fine
いつも傍で笑っていてよ
Always smiling by my side
あなたのすぐ傍で…
Right by your side...
あなたは今どこで何をしていますか
Where are you now, what are you doing?
この空の続く場所にいますか
Are you in the place where this sky goes on?
君がいない日々の意味を今知って
Now I know the meaning of days without you...
すべて何もかも捨てて駆け出してた
I threw everything away and ran off.
星の下で今も心は飲み込んで
Beneath the stars, my heart is still swallowed up,
誰かのためだけに笑ってるの？
smiling only for someone else's sake?
君の生まれた町向かい風の歩道橋の上
On the pedestrian bridge facing the wind in your hometown,
背中押す懐かしい歌
an old familiar song pushes me forward.
この目に見えない感情がこんなにこの胸を
These invisible feelings fill my chest so much
熱くする満たしていく壊れるくらいに
and warm it, fulfilling it until it breaks.
雨の日も風の日も忘れてなかった
Even on rainy or windy days, I never forgot
涙で濡れた笑顔
your smile wet with tears.
失くせない何よりも大事なモノ
Something more precious than anything else I cannot lose.
いつか君と夜空のふたつの星に
Someday, you and I, to two stars in the night sky,
名前つけて交わした指切り
we gave names and exchanged a pinky promise.
キミはしずかに流れる星を探した
You quietly searched for a shooting star,
ずっと僕の願いを祈ってた
always praying for my wish.
幸せにならなきゃいけない人のために
For the sake of those who must find happiness,
星は夜に輝く
the stars shine in the night.
逢いたくて
I want to see you...
はい、ということで、どうでしょうか？
Yes, so, how was it?
団長の浴衣になります！ちょっとね、大人っぽい感じ？
It's Dancho's yukata! A bit mature?
でも子供っぽい感じ、どんな感じでしょうか？
But also childlike, what kind of vibe is it?
いつもわちゃわちゃしてる動きなんで子供っぽくなっちゃうんですけど、
I'm always moving around all hyper, so it feels childish, but...
えっと、花火と浴衣を聞いていただきましたーー！
um, I sang "Fireworks and Yukata" for you!
いや本当に夏にぴったりな曲だなと思っていて、団長この曲すごく好きなので、こうやって浴衣で歌えて良かったです。
Really, I thought it was such a fitting song for summer, and Dancho loves this song so much, so I'm glad I could sing it in a yukata.
ちょっとね、あの、座りでね、ちょっと歌って踊るってことあんまりないから、新鮮だったんじゃないかなって思います。
Also, you don't often see me singing and dancing sitting down, so I thought it might feel pretty fresh.
この後ね、ちょっとまたお着替えをして、別のところで、あの、歌って踊りますので、最後までよろしくお願いいたします！
After this, I'll change my clothes and sing and dance somewhere else, so please look forward to it until the end!
では、また！ちょっと、まだまだ続くのでまた着替えてくるんでね！
Well then, see you! It's still continuing, so I'll go change again!
clock lock works
[Title: clock lock works]
パッパと働く休むことなくロイドロロランランラン
Working briskly without rest, ro-do-ro-do, ran-ran-ran.
繰り返しの毎日気が付けば迷子の猫の様
Every day repeats, before I knew it, like a lost cat.
どっかで誰かが入れ替わろうとマノマノランランラン
Somewhere someone tries to take my place, ma-no-ma-no, ran-ran-ran.
誰も気が付かないひたすらに数字を追いかけた
Nobody notices, earnestly chasing after numbers.
心の奥底には鍵をかけた扉
In the depths of my heart, a locked door.
「馬鹿やってる」そう言い聞かせては
Telling myself "How foolish,"
ノックの音を無視した
I ignored the knocking sound.
「変わらない」と諦めて佇む時計の針に急かされる
Giving up with "It won't change," hurried by the lingering hands of the clock.
夢ならば喜んで「星に願いを」と真面目な顔で
If it's a dream, gladly with a serious face saying "Make a wish upon a star,"
チクタク働け馬鹿げた兵士がタンタンランランラン
working tick-tock, foolish soldiers, tan-tan-ran-ran-ran.
取捨選択よーいどん気が付けば真っ黒煤の様
Choice and selection, ready set go, before I know it like pitch-black soot.
朝と夜とが入れ替わろうとノマノマランランラン
Even if morning and night switch places, no-ma-no-ma, ran-ran-ran.
誰も気にしない貪欲に数字を追いかけた
Nobody cares, avariciously chasing after numbers.
扉の向こうから微かに漏れる声
From the other side of the door, a voice faintly leaks.
「仕方ない」と膝立てて部屋の隅っこで小さく罵声を吐く
Pulling my knees up saying "It can't be helped" and spitting curses in the corner of the room.
何処でもいい連れ出して王子様なんて来るはずも無く
Take me anywhere, even though no prince will ever come.
「こんばんはおはようございます」扉の向こうで誰かが言う
"Good evening, good morning," someone says on the other side of the door.
「大丈夫鍵は開けずともここからアナタに届くでしょ？」
"It's alright, even without unlocking, it will reach you from here, right?"
パッパラ働く休むことなく
Working "pappara" without a rest,
ロ・ド・ロ・ド ランランラ
lo-do-lo-do, lan-lan-lah.
繰り返しの毎日
Every day is a repetition,
気が付けば迷子の猫の様
before you know it, like a stray cat.
どこかで誰かが入れ替わろうと
Somewhere, someone tries to take your place—
マ・ノ・マ・ノ ランランラ
ma-no-ma-no, lan-lan-lah.
誰も気が付かない
No one even notices, needlessly
ひたすらに数字を追いかけた
chasing numbers single-mindedly.
心の奥底には
Deep inside your heart's core
鍵をかけた扉
is a locked door.
「馬鹿げてる」そう言い聞かせては
Telling yourself, "How ridiculous,"
「こんばんは、おはようございます」
"Good evening, and good morning,"
扉の向こうで誰かが言う
someone says from beyond the door.
「大丈夫、鍵は開けずとも」
"It's fine, even without opening the lock,"
「ここからアナタに届くでしょ？」
"it will reach you from here, right?"
そんな話は聞きたくない
That's just talk I don't want to hear,
聞きたくない
don't want to hear—
いや聞き たくない
no, I don't want to hear it.
ねえねえ 何処にも行かないで
Hey, hey, don't go anywhere,
側にいて 話を聞かせて
stay by my side and let me hear your story.
「下らない」と嘘ついて
Lying that "it's worthless,"
それでも誰かに気付いて欲しくて
still wanting someone to notice me,
冷たくて触れたくない
cold and unwilling to touch.
いつまで経っても鍵は開けられずに
No matter how long passes, the lock won't open,
棺の中で働いて
working inside a coffin.
「それでもまあ」なんて言いたくはないわ
I don't want to say, "Well, even so..."
針は回る いつまでも
The hands spin on, forever and ever,
優しいノックの音で泣いてしまう
weeping at the sound of a gentle knock.
だんご だんご だんご だんご だんご だんご 大家族
Dango, dango, dango, dango, dango, a great dango family!
だんご だんご だんご だんご だんご 大家族
Dango, dango, dango, dango, a great dango family!
だんご 大家族
Dango, a great family!
だんご だんご だんご だんご だんご 大家族
Dango, dango, dango, dango, a great dango family!
やんちゃな 焼きだんご
The naughty roasted dango,
やさしい あんだんご
the kind red bean dango,
少し 夢見がち な 月見だんご
the moon-viewing dango, a bit dreamy.
おすまし ごまだんご
The prim sesame dango,
四つ子 串だんご
the four dango on a skewer.
みんな みんな あわせて 100人家族
Everyone comes together as a family of 100.
赤ちゃん だんご は いつも 幸せ の 中 で
The baby dango is always wrapped in happiness,
年寄り だんご は 目 を 細め て いる
the elderly dango has its eyes narrowed in a smile.
なかよし だんご 手 を つなぎ 大きな まるい 輪 に なる よ
Chummy dango hold hands to form a big, round ring.
町 を つくり だんご 星 の 上 みんな で 笑い あう よ
They build a town on the dango planet, laughing together.
うさぎ も そら で 手 を ふって みてりゅ でっかい おつきさま
The rabbit waves from the sky to the huge moon.
うれしい こと かなしい こと も 全部 まるめて
Embracing all happy and sad things alike,
なかよし だんご 手 を つなぎ 大きな まるい 輪 に なる よ
chummy dango hold hands to form a big, round ring.
町 を つくり だんご 星 の 上 みんな で 笑い あう よ
They build a town on the dango planet, laughing together.
うさぎ も そら で 手 を ふって みてりゅ でっかい おつきさま
The rabbit waves from the sky to the huge moon.
うれしい こと かなしい こと も 全部 まるめて
Embracing all happy and sad things alike.
だんご だんご だんご だんご だんご だんご 大家族
Dango, dango, dango, dango, dango, a great dango family!
Dango, dango, dango, dango, dango, dango, great big dango family.
やんちゃな焼きだんご やさしいあんだんご
Mischievous roasted dango, gentle bean-jam dango,
すこし夢見がちな月見だんご
Moon-watching dango that tends to be a dreamer,
おすましごま団子 四つ子串団子
Prim sesame dango, quadruplet dangos on a stick,
みんなみんなあわせて100人家族
Put them all together, a family of 100.
赤ちゃんだんごは いつも幸せの中で
The baby dango is always surrounded by happiness,
年寄りだんごは 目を細めてる
The elderly dango is narrowing its eyes.
なかよしだんご 手をつなぎ大きなまるい輪になるよ
Companionable dango, join hands and form a big round circle.
町をつくり だんご星の上 みんなで笑いあうよ
Making a town, laughing together on the dango star.
うさぎもそらで 手をふってみてる でっかいお月さま
Even the rabbit in the sky waves its hands at the big moon.
うれしいこと 悲しいことも 全部まるめて
Wrapping up all happy things and sad things together,
だんご だんご だんご だんご だんご だんご 大家族
Dango, dango, dango, dango, dango, dango, great big dango family.
はい、ということで みんな見えてる？ あ、待って、画面が赤いで...
Alright, so everyone, can you see me? Ah, wait, the screen is red—
あれ、みんなのコメントが見えない。 ちょっと、ちょっと待ってね。
Huh, I can't see anyone's comments. Hold on, wait a second.
あ、痛い痛い！ ああ、みんな、めちゃめちゃ拍手してくれてる！ ありがとう！
Ah, ouch ouch! Ah, everyone is clapping so much! Thank you!
今日はね、あの、いつもと違って、収録と生パートのね、こう、2つでやっております。
Today, unlike usual, we're doing this with two parts: a prerecorded part and a live part.
こちら、はい、コメント見えておりますので、いや、ありがとうございます！
Here, yep, I can see your comments, so thank you so much!
なんかみんなね、コメントでね、なんかすごい夏を感じたり、エモさを感じたりね、
It feels like everyone is feeling the summer vibes and nostalgia in the comments,
いろんな感情が爆発してる感じで、団長嬉しいなと。
with all kinds of emotions exploding, and it makes Dancho so happy.
思い返せば、このセトリは4ヶ月前だから、う、4月、3月ぐらいに考えたセトリなって、
Come to think of it, I thought of this setlist 4 months ago, around April or March,
おります！では、ちょっとね、ここから、ちょっと3つお知らせがあるんですけど、それ聴いてくれますか？
so there you go! Now, I have three announcements starting from here, will you listen to them?
ちなみにね、ここも尺があるので駆け足になりますが、ではお知らせ1つ目！
By the way, we've got time constraints so I'll go fast, but announcement number one!
どどんが、どーーーーん！
Drumroll, boom!
はい、みんな待ってたかな？ 活動3周年記念、ということでグッズを出したいと思います。
Yes, I wonder if everyone was waiting for this? I'd like to release merchandise for my 3rd anniversary.
8月8日が、あの3周年だったんですけど、このライブに合わせてね、ちょっと遅らせてグッズを販売する感じになりました。
August 8th was my 3rd anniversary, but we ended up delaying the merchandise sales to coincide with this live stream.
じゃあちょっと、あのかな、詳しいあの商品とかを紹介していきたいと思うんですけれど、
So, I'd like to introduce the detailed products and stuff, but—
そう時期室ね、サインとかもあります。あ、見えてる！あ、ちょっ、あ、ちょっとこれ、見せちゃおうかな。
right, there are hand-signed items and such too. Ah, I can see it! Ah, wait, should I show this?
どん！ということで、ちょっとね、あ、なんかちっちゃいラインさんがいるんですけど、
Ta-da! So, um, there's a tiny Danin-san here,
ちょっとその、団さん気になると思うんですが、こちら活動3周年記念フルセットの中身になります。
and you're probably curious about them, but this is the contents of the 3rd anniversary full set.
えっと、まあ今ね、ちょっと制服で紹介させていただくんですけど、つい最近ね、新衣装をお披露めしました。
Um, well, I'm introducing it in my uniform right now, but I recently debuted my new outfit.
その新衣装に合わせた、なんと団長とおそろいパーカーが、あります、え？
Matching that new outfit, there is, believe it or not, a matching hoodie with Dancho, eh?
え？マジ？まって、まって、まってという事でみんなさんちょっとぜひ、あの
Eh? Seriously? Wait, wait, wait, so everyone please—
団長とおそろっちになってくださる、このサムネもね、あの団長のパーカーに合わせてもらっておりますのでぜひぜひ買ってきてください！
Please match with Dancho! This thumbnail is also matched to Dancho's hoodie, so please definitely go get it!
で、えっと、ます、団員専用シェイカー、マッスルシェイカーもあります。
And, um, there's also the Danin-exclusive shaker, a muscle shaker.
これもね、あの、夏の思い出ということで綿を父上が描いたアクリルパネル、ポストカード、
This too, as a memory of summer, features an acrylic panel and postcard illustrated by Wata-chichi-ue,
あの、あるんですけど、まあ夏と言ったらね、汗かくんで、汗かいたらちゃんとタンパク質を補給しましょうみたいな
and, well, speaking of summer, you sweat, so once you sweat, you should properly replenish protein, something like that!
感じで、こちら気になってたでしょ？見て、団員さんぬいぐるみキーホルダー、こちらね、あの今回、その、団員さん
So, you were curious about this, right? Look, the Danin-san plushie keychain! This time, um, that Danin-san—
あのライブでも左右にいたと思うんですが、あ！かわいい！このぐらいのサイズ感、もうちょっと、もしかしたらちっちゃいかなって感じなんですけど、
I think they were on both sides during the live too, ah! Cute! This kind of size, or maybe a little smaller,
こんぐらいになっておりますので、これね、ぜひぜひあのカバンにつけて、あの「俺団員だ」というアピールをしてください！めちゃくちゃかわいい！
is what it's like, so please definitely attach this to your bag and appeal that "I'm a Danin!" It's super cute!
団員さん、おしり隠したいんですけどちょっと...
Guild members, I want to hide my butt, but...
あー！ありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Ah! Thank you so much! Thank you!
ちょっとおしり隠そうとしたら引きになっちゃった。
When I tried to hide my butt, the camera zoomed out.
こちらね、あのぜひぜひめちゃめちゃ可愛いので、
This one is super, super cute, so...
はーい、ぜひ、お買い求めください！
Yes, please be sure to purchase it!
ということでね、時間が結構バタバタなんですけど、
So, we're pretty rushed on time, but
よいしょ、ちょっと、団員さんどこに置こう？えっ、あっでも持とっか！
Let's see, where should I put the mascot? Oh, I'll just hold it!
もっ、かわいそうだからもっとこうかな？じゃあ持ちながらちょっと紹介したいと思います。
Poor thing, maybe put it here? I'll introduce them while holding it.
あと2つあるんですけど、
There are two more, but
ええと、もう1個が、この後22時15分から、ええと、団長初めての生面言3Dをしたいと思います！
Starting at 22:15 tonight, I'll be doing Danchou's very first live unmasked 3D stream!
いやあ、ちょっと3D生ってね、どんな感じになるのか、ちょっとドキドキなんですけど、
Man, doing a 3D stream... I'm a bit nervous about how it'll turn out,
たくさんね、あのメンバーギフトとかも配ってくれてありがとう。あとメンバーさんになってくれた方もありがとう！
Thank you for giving out member gifts and everything. And thank you to those who became members!
いっぱいね、ちょっと衣装もありますので、その撮影会をしたいと思います。
There are lots of outfits too, so we'll be having a photo session.
ええと、その撮影会は、あのスクショはオッケーです。Twitterでたくさんスクショをやるのはオッケーなんですけど、切り抜きとか映像はダメになっておりますので、ぜひぜひいっぱいスクショしてください！
As for that photo session, screenshots are okay, but clipping or video recording is not allowed, so please take lots of screenshots!
ということで、あやべ！めちゃめちゃ時間押してるんですけど、最後、
So—ah, oh no! We're running super late on time, but lastly,
最後のお知らせです。この後ちょっと1曲歌わせていただくんですけど、最後に、団長おり曲歌います！
here's the final announcement. I'll be singing one song shortly, and lastly, Danchou's original song!
おり曲は、こちらです！はい、どんどん作詞作曲古川本舗さんの「ours」という曲を歌わせていただきます。
The original song is this one! Yes, composed and written by Furukawa Honpo, titled "ours".
この後ね、22時5分からミュージックビデオも配信されるんですけど、
Starting at 22:05 tonight, the music video will also be premiered, but
この「ours」、すごい良い曲になってて、古川本舗さんっていうね、あの有名な方がいるんですけど、
this "ours" is such a wonderful song, and there's this famous person named Furukawa Honpo,
なぜその方にお願いしたかと言うと、団長ね「眠る魚」という曲が好きで、その「眠る魚」好きだから、その、なんかそういう「眠る魚」のような、ゆったりとした、そしてエモい曲が作れたいということでお願いいたしました。
and why I asked him is because Danchou loves the song "Nemuru Sakana", so I wanted to create a relaxed and emotional song like that.
こちらね歌詞に注目していただくとすごいんですけど、「ours」はね、まあ、団員さんと団長の3年間の振り返りと、4年目もねずっと一緒に繋がろうといった想いが込められた曲になっておりますのでね、もうめちゃめちゃ気持ちを込めて歌うのでよろしくお願いします！
"ours" is filled with feelings of looking back on the 3 years and wanting to stay connected into the 4th year, so I'll sing it with all my heart!
本日24時からデジタルリリースもします！これからおひろめするのでよろしくお願いします。ということで1分オーバーしました！
Starting at midnight today, the digital release will also drop! We'll be promoting it from now on, so thanks for your support. So, we went 1 minute over!
これが生！ということで、あの、はけたいと思います。じゃあ、一緒に見ようね。あっ、団長歌うんだ。じゃあ、よろしくねー！
This is live! So, I'll be heading off stage. Let's watch it together. Well then, see you!
今日はこのままさよならじゃないよ
手を撮ってくれたなら
Today isn't a goodbye like this,
If you took my hand,
秘密も眠りにつくような夜に
君を連れていくよ
I'll take you to a night
where even secrets fall asleep.
それは例えば、遠く離れていたって
手をつないでいられるような
奇跡のような話をしよう！
Like a story of a miracle,
where even if we're far apart, we can hold hands!
窓は開けておいて。
Leave the window open.
今日までを思い出して
一つ一つ並べたら
When I remember up to today
and line them up one by one,
明日の雨が気になり出して
どうも眠れないみたいだ。
I start worrying about tomorrow's rain
and somehow can't seem to sleep.
変わりたくないことや
変わらなきゃいけないことも
Things I don't want to change,
and things that must change,
少し荒れたまま
窓の外を眺めていたんだ。
I looked out the window,
feeling a bit unsettled.
雨が降り出すその前に
君のところまで行けるような気がして
目を閉じてみたんだ。
Before the rain starts to fall,
feeling like I could reach you,
I closed my eyes.
そして、このまま遠くへ行こう！
手をとってくれるから。
秘密も眠りにつくような夜を
君と泳いでいくよ。
And let's go far away just like this!
Because you'll take my hand.
I'll swim with you through a night
where even secrets fall asleep.
街の明かりが消える度に笑って
路地裏で抱き合おう。
馬鹿みたいな話をしよう！
窓は開けておいて。聞こえる？
Laughing every time the city lights go out,
let's hug in the alleyway.
Let's talk about silly things!
Leave the window open. Can you hear me?
聞こえる？
Can you hear me?
愛おしいことや
無くせないものを
Things precious to me,
and things I can't lose,
今日みたいな
Like today,
夜を重ねて 織り上げてきた
We've woven together night after night,
私たちに響く音
A sound that echoes within us.
夜が来るたびに 心が踊ってしまうのは
Every time night falls, the reason my heart dances
また一つ 重なっていくから
is because another piece piles up inside.
目を閉じてみたんだ
I tried closing my eyes.
今夜 私たちだけで眠ろう。
Tonight, let's sleep just the two of us—
誰にも言わないで。
don't tell anyone.
君が眠りにつく その少し前に
Just a little before you drift off to sleep,
名前を呼んで
call my name.
叶わない願いに胸は痛んで 俯いてしまうけど
Though unfulfilled wishes make my chest ache and make me look down,
誰もいない街へ 誘いに行くから
I'm coming to invite you to a town where no one else is.
今日は このままさよならじゃないよ。
Today isn't a final goodbye.
手をとってくれたなら
If you take my hand,
秘密も 眠りにつくような夜に 君を連れていくよ。
I'll take you to a night where even secrets drift off to sleep.
それは例えば、遠く離れていたって
Even if we were far apart, for instance,
手をつないでいられるような 奇跡のような話をしよう！
let's talk about a miracle where we can still hold hands!
窓は開けておいて。聞こえる？
Keep the window open. Can you hear it?
愛しいことや 無くせないものを教えてくれたのは
What taught me precious things and things I can't lose
今日みたいな
was like today,
夜を重ねて 織り上げてきた
weaving together night after night,
私たちに響く音、
a sound echoing within us,
響く言葉。
words echoing.